Guide to the Robert Compton Papers
The Wittliff Collections
Robert Compton Papers
1955-2008
The Wittliff Collections https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Compton, Robert C.
SWWC.107
28 boxes
16 Linear Feet
The Robert Compton papers span 1955-2008 and document the career of the well-respected and long-time Books editor of the Dallas Morning News. The bulk of the collection is the correspondences from book reviewers, journalists, and authors, including Jim Lehrer, Larry McMurtry, Rick Bass, and William Goyen. This collection also is comprised of documents that pertain to the inner-workings of the Dallas Morning News, including changes in writing styles pertaining to race and gender. The collection also contains photographs, cassette tape recordings, and fragile newspapers.
Scope and Contents
The Robert "Bob" Compton Collection includes documents that cover the years 1955 through 2008. The collection contains 28 boxes and is 16 linear feet. There are four series within this collection: Series I – Compton Personal Papers, Series II – Correspondence, Series III – Dallas Morning News, and Series IV – Newspapers and Magazines. There are two subseries within Series III. The first of the two subseries is Pre-1976, prior to the creation of the Focus section. This includes Compton's career as a Reporter and Assistant Editor. The second subseries includes the dates 1976-1998, Compton's career as Focus and Books Editor. This is the largest of the two subseries. Much of Compton's Collection has been maintained in its original filing order to maintain the integrity of the collection. However, the contents within the folders have been organized either alphabetically or chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
Gift of Bob Compton, 2010
Biographical Note
Robert "Bob" Compton is a fifth generation Texan. He graduated from Teague High School in 1944. Compton attended Texas A&M University from 1944 through 1945, when he left to join the United States Navy. Compton served in the United States Navy from 1945 through 1945. He then entered Southern Methodist University, majoring in Journalism. He graduated in 1949 and began his first newspaper job as a Reporter for the Pampa (Texas) Daily News. Compton worked at the Pampa Daily News until 1950, when the Garland Daily News (later changed to the Garland Herald) hired him as a Reporter. Compton worked as a Reporter for the Garland Daily News until 1956.
In 1956, the Dallas Morning News hired Compton as a General Assignments Reporter. He worked in this position until 1957, when he was promoted to Assistant Editor. Compton served in this capacity until 1976, when he created and became Editor of the Focus section of the Dallas Morning News. This section included news analysis and special features. In 1982, the Dallas Morning News assigned Compton to be editor of the Books section. Compton served as Editor of both sections until the Focus was discontinued in 1984. Compton acted as Editor of the Books section, as well as Special Assignments Editor from 1984 through 1990. Compton continued as the Books Editor of the Book Pages section of the Dallas Morning News from 1990 until his retirement in 1998. Through Compton's employment at the Dallas Morning News, he initiated and maintained correspondences with many influential and well-known journalists and writers, including Jim Lehrer, Larry McMurtry, and William Goyen. His correspondences show long-lasting working relationships, as well as friendships, based on respect and mutual admiration. While acting as Books Editor, Compton was responsible for determining policies regarding book reviewers. Through his tenure at the Dallas Morning News, Compton developed well-respected and recognized sections of the Dallas Morning News.
Compton has been a member of the National books Critics Circle, the Texas Institute of Letters, and the Texas Folklore Society. While serving as Books Editor, Compton helped launch the Poetry in Motion program in Dallas, Texas, in 1998. He received the Media Award from the Book Publishers of Texas Association in 1988. In 2012, Compton was named a Living Legend of North Texas Journalism.
Index Terms
Subjects
Books -- Reviews
Document Types
Journalism -- Texas
- Personal Papers, 1975-2001; 2937
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains Compton's personal papers. Included in this series is Compton's own recounting of his career as the Focus and Books Editor for the Dallas Morning News. Also within this series are correspondences relating to Compton's retirement.
  - Career, 2938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Contents
    Informal recounting of Compton's career at Dallas Morning News, listing of donation to Wittliff Collection, honors, letters of congratulations, photograph
  - Retirement: Letters of congratulations, photographs, 2939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1955-2008
  Series Description
  Series II is comprised of correspondences to and from Compton and book reviewers, publishers, authors, and poets. Within this series are six subject files including: John Graves, William Humphrey, Cormac McCarthy, James Michener, William Morris, and Bryan Woolley. Of particular interest in this series are correspondences that show authors prior to their renowned success. Many of the authors were book reviewers early in their careers. Some of these authors include: Rick Bass, Gene Fowler, William Goyen, A.C. Greene, Steve Harrigan, Shelby Hearon, Elmer Kelton, Beverly Lowry, Larry McMurtry, Paul S. Malone, Jay Milner, Jan Reid, Clay Reynolds, Joyce Roach, C.W. Smith, W.K. Stratton, R.G. Vliet, Donley Watt, and Ed Weems. Compton also received correspondences from the following Texas writers: Judy Alter, Neal Barrett Jr., Sandra Brown, Mark Busby, and Celia Morris. In addition, this series illustrates the close-knit community between authors, publishers, and editors, with many of the letters referring to fellow authors and so forth.
  - A - B, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Agrella, Catherine; Allen, C. Leonard; Alter, Judy; Anderson, Kerby; Angle, Jim; Arthur, Elizabeth; Bailey, Ronald; Baldwin, Dan; Barclay, Linda; Barrett, Neal; Barton, Frances; Bender, Eileen T.; Benedict, Elizabeth; Berk, Sally Ann; Bernstein, Dennis; Billue, Sylva; Black, Baxter; Bloom, John; Bonnell, Pamela; Boothe, Ben B.; Brans, Jo; Broch, Nathan; Bromley, Larry; Brown, Martha; Brown, Sandra; Bunkley, Anita; Burrows, M. Denise; Burson, Lynn; Busby, Mark; Includes correspondences from book reviewers, thank you notes from authors, and requests from authors
  - Abernethy, F.E. [TX Folklore Society, Stephen F. Austin State Univ.], 1982-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Correspondences about book reviews and folklore society
  - Albright, J. F. Bliss, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Correspondence about ABA Newswire
  - Albritton, Claude [Southern Methodist University], 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Correspondence about book reviews
  - Anderson, Patrick, 1981-1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Correspondence about book reviews, newspaper clipping
  - Anderson, Roger [University of Texas at Tyler], 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bass, Rick (2 folders), 1986-2006 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), personal letters, photographs, cassette tape
  - Bauman, Jon, 1992-2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Correspondence about books written (author)
  - Baxter, Gordon, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Correspondence about book reviews (journalist)
  - Bennett, Patrick [McMurry College], 1981-1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author)
  - Berryhill, Michael, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Baird, Sarah, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Correspondence about books written (author), photographs
  - Blickle, Katrina and Michael Pellechia, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brandon, Jay, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Buckley, Chris, 1979-1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Buford, William, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Correspondence about book reviews, poems written (poet), photograph
  - Burns, Gerald, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Correspondence about poems written (poet)
  - Byrd, Jim [East Texas University], 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - C - D, 1976-1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Campbell, Ewing; ____, Carla; Carney, Paul; Carstarphen, Meta G.; Carter, George F.; Castleberry, Vivian; Cattarulla, K.; Chapman, John S.; Christison, Kathleen; Clem, Julie and Onnee; Cobb, William J.; Cockrell, Jane; Cogan, Neil H.; Coggins, Paul; Cohen, Barry Mendel; Cohen, Harlan P.; Conroy, Mary; Cooper, H.H.A.; Cooper, Richard A.; Cowling, Will; Crim, W.R. (Billy Bob); Currier, Jameson; Davis, Barbara Kerr; Davis, Stewart; Dodson, Michael; Doggett, DeWitt; Donovan, Jim; Dooley, Sally; Dorn, Fred J.; Douglas, Deborah; Downs, Fane; Dupree, John C.; Dumas, Lloyd (Jeff); Correspondence about book reviews, books written (authors), thank you letters, complaints about reviews, letters from publishers
  - Callahan, North, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Campbell, Scott, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Capps, Ben, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Carleton, Don [University of Texas at Austin], 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Carper, Leslie, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Correspondence about book reviews, photograph
  - Carr, Camilla, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Correspondence about books written (author), photograph
  - Cheuse, Alan, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Christian, George, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Christman, Calvin [Cedar Valley College], 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Correspondence recommending book reviewers
  - Chute, Carolyn, 1984-2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Clifford, Craig [Tarleton State University], 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Clifton, Daniel [Chronicle Publications], 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Correspondence between editors
  - Cochran, Mike, 1987-1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Correspondence (journalist)
  - Comer, Suzanne [Southern Methodist University Press], 1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Colquitt, Betsy [Texas Christian University], 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Condon, Richard, 1981-1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), photographs
  - Coomer, Joe, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), newspaper clipping
  - Covici, Pascal, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Correspondence about writings (journalist)
  - Cox, Mike, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Correspondence about articles written (journalist), copies of articles
  - Cullum, Lee, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Curtis, Tom, 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Compton's personal writing about Curtis, correspondence about articles written (journalist), magazine
  - Dary, David [University of Kansas], 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Deaton, John, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Correspondence about book reviews, articles written (journalist)
  - Dewlen, Al, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dodge, Tom [Mountain View College], 1978-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Donnelly, Katherine, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dorris, Michael, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dugger, Ronnie, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - E - H, 1970-2002 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Elliott, Norbert; Elmblad, Mary; Erisman, Fred; Farmer, David; Fensch, Thomas; Ficklen, Mary; Floornoy, Craig; Foreman, Paul; Fox, H.B.; Foxworth, Sarah Payne; Frailey, Dave; Frame, Helen Dunn; Frome, Michael; George, Ronald; Gibson, George L.; Goldsborough, Dick; Grauer, Neil A.; Grigsby, Larry; Gunnell, Donna M.; H____, K.C.; Hall, M.T.; Hankins, Bailey; Haag, Marty; Harpham, Edward J.; Hazelwood, Katherine, Hershorn, Tad; Hester, Don; Holksema, Thomas; Hogle, James; Holland, Max; Holmes, Marjorie; Hong, Terry; Houck, Jim; Howell, Charlene; Hubbard, ____; Hughes, M.E.; Humphreys, Joel Don; Hunt, Caroline; Hunter, Bill; Correspondence about book reviews, books written (authors), thank you letters, complaints about reviews, requests from authors
  - Ennis, Michael, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Farenthold, Sissey [Wells College], 1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Faulk, John Henry, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fehrenbach, T.R., 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Flynn, Robert [Trinity University], 1987-2006 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Follett, Ken, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Fowler, Gene, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Frantz, Joe [University of Texas at Austin], 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Furman, Laura, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Garcia, Ed, 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Geeslin, Campbell, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Gent, Pete, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Gibbons, Reginald, 1985-1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Correspondence about book reviews, poems written (poet)
  - Gibson, William [Southern Methodist University], 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Goetzmann, William [University of Texas at Austin], 1988 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Gordon, Roxy, 1983-2000 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Correspondence about books reviews, books written, cassette tape, photograph
  - Gould, Joe [Dallas Morning News], 1971-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Correspondence about books reviews, books written (author), articles written (journalist), six photographs, newspaper clippings
  - Goyen, William, 1955-1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), with his wife (Doris Roberts, Actress), five photographs, newspaper clippings
  - Graham, Don [University of Texas at Austin], 1984-1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Grant, Lyman, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Graves, John, 1980-2004 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Subject file about books written (author), six photographs, newspaper clippings
  - Gray, A.W, 1988-1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Green, Subie [Texas Christian University], 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Gregory, Keith [Southern Methodist University], 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Correspondence about directory of SMU Press
  - Greene, A.C, 1982-1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Grove, Lloyd, 1979-1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Correspondence about articles written (journalist)
  - Guice, John [University of Southern Mississippi], 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Gunter, Pete [North Texas State University], 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Haily, Betsy, 1959-1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), photograph, newspaper clipping, information regarding Oliver Haily, Brooke Haily
  - Hale, Leon, 1979-1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Haley, J. Evetts, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Correspondence regarding Rosalind Kress Haley Library
  - Haley, James, 1981-1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), includes unfinished letter to Oliver Haley, 1959
  - Hamric, Roy [University of Texas at Arlington], 1982-2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Hardberger, Phil, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Hardesty, Robert [Southwest Texas State University], 1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Harrigan, Steve [Texas Monthly], 1980-1999 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Harris, Leon, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Hearon, Shelby, 1979-1995 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), photograph
  - Heath, Layne, 1987-1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Heat Moon, William Least, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Hillerman, Tony [University of New Mexico], 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written
  - Hinojosa-Smith, Rolando, 1982-1996 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Hoggard, Jim, 1982-1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Holley, Joe, 1981-1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), between editors
  - Huff, Tom, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Correspondence about books written (author), includes information about Jennifer Wilde
  - Humphrey, William, 1989-1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Subject file about books written (author)
  - Hurt, Harry, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - I - L, 1976-1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Isaacs, Arnold, K.; James, Caryn; January, Frank; Johnson, Tom; Johnston, Richard E.; Jun, Kathleen M.; Kafka, Paul; Katz, Todd; Kay, Mary; ____, Kelly; Kennelly, Laura B.; Kerr, J.; Kilgore, Richard B.; Klein, Gerald J.; Kotz, Nick; Kraeplin, Camille R.; Lalla, Bill; Lang, Kathryn M.; Lange, Pam; LaSalle, Peter; ____, Laura; Lauricella, Francis E.; Ledbetter, Mindi; ____, Leslie; Lincecum, Jerry B.; Lo, Steven C.; Logan, Liz; Long, Douglas K.; Long, Julian; Longfellow, David; Lynskey, Edward C.; Lynum, Curtis O.; Correspondence about Book reviews, books written (author), thank you letters, requests from authors, complaints about book reviews
  - Johnson, Greg, 1985-1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Correspondence about books reviews, books written (author)
  - Johnson, William Weber, 1980-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books and articles written (author and journalist), newspaper clippings Compton's notes: See Elizabeth Ann McMurray
  - Jones, G. William [Southern Methodist University], 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Kanellos, Nick [University of Houston], 1988 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Kelton, Elmer, 1981-1988 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - King, Stephen [Philtrum Press, Owner], 1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Correspondence about publishing, Don Robertson
  - Koster, Rick, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lacy, Allen [Stockton State College], 1979-1987 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Leaton, Anne, 1984-1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Lee, James Ward, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Lehrer, Jim, 1989-2006 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Correspondence about news articles (journalist), personal correspondence
  - Letts, Billie, 1995-1999 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Lindsey, David, 1980-1998 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Lopez, Barry, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author
  - Lowe, Richard [North Texas State University], 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Lowry, Beverly, 1981-1989 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Lyman, Lloyd [Texas A&M Press], undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Correspondence about publishing
  - M, 1975-1998 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    McCartney, Scott; McCombs, Holland; McFarland, Keith D.; McGrain, Linda; McQuarrie, Jack; Magnino, Lisa L.; Magerino, Susan; Maloy, Robert; Martin, Amy; Martin, Gyde; Martin, W.B.J.; Maurice, S. Charles; Middleton, David; Middleton, Mary Margaret; Milam, Michael; Milan, Karen; Milazzo, Lee; Miller, ____; Miller, Jan; Miller, Zack; Milligan, Mike; Mills, Helen L.; Mills, Hilary; Mitchell, Glenn; Moeller, Beverley; Moore, Dennis; Morris, Anne; Morris, Celia; Morthland, John; Mosley, Richard; Murchison, Bill; Murphy, Patrick; Musgrove, Stanley; Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), author requests, thank you letters, newspaper clippings
  - MacKintosh, Prudence, 1980-1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - McCarthy, Cormac, 1992-2006 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Subject file about books written (author) and newspaper clipping
  - McDonald, Walt, 1988-2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Correspondence about poems written (poet), newspaper clipping
  - McFadden, Dennis [University of Texas at Austin], 1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - McGinnis, Bruce [Amarillo College], 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - McLean, Malcolm [University of Texas at Arlington], 1980-1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - McMurray, Elizabeth H., 1980-1994 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Correspondence about bookstore, newspaper clippings, copies of newspaper articles (1951-1958) Compton's notes: See Wm. Weber Johnson
  - McMurtry, Larry, 1983-2005 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), and letters of complaint regarding interviews
  - McNamee, Laurence [East Texas State University], 1978-2006 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Correspondence about books written (author), four photographs, newspaper clipping
  - McNeely, David, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Correspondence about articles (journalist)
  - Malone, Paul S., 1992-2000 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Marcus, Stanley, 1982-1998 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books published (publisher)
  - Marks, Paula, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Matusow, Allen [Rice University], 1984 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Maverick, Maury, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Maxwell, Allenk [Dallas Morning News], 1979-1981 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Correspondence about book editor of newspaper
  - Mewshaw, Michael [U. of TX at Austin, American Acad. in Rome], 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Michener, James, 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Miller, Vassar, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Correspondence about poems written (poet), newspaper clippings
  - Milligan, Bryce, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Milner, Jay, 1979-1985 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Morris, Willie, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Subject file about books written, photograph
  - Moss, Chuck, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Mossiker, Frances, 1979-1985 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written, photograph,
  - Nathaniel, Isabel, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Nichols, Peggy, 1979-1998 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Nye, Naomi Shehab, 1982-1995 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Correspondence about book reviews, poems written (poet), photographs
  - O - P, 1976-1994 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Oldham, Virginia L.; Orms, Tom; Ornish, Natalie; Osborne, Burl; Patterson, Paige; Pederson, Rena; Perdue, Richard M.; Perry, Thomas A.; Peterson, Jane; Phillips, Warren H.; Pimm, Lilian C.; Pitts, Joe W.; Potts, Terry; Preston, Harry; Price, Deb; ____, Priscilla; Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), thank you notes, complaints about book reviews
  - Osborn, Carolyn, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Correspondence about suggested book reviewer
  - Owens, William A., 1982-1988 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), four photographs
  - Payne, Darwin, 1985-1996 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Perrine, Laurence, 1986-1990 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Pilkington, Tom, 1986-1998 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Pringle, Terry, 1982-1996 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    Correspondence about book reviews, books written (author), newspaper clippings
  - Purvis, Hoyt [University of Arkansas], 1984-1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Q - R, 1983-1990 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Quaid, Glenn; Rapaport, Richard; Ray, Karen; Reed, Ronald; Reyes, Angel; Rice, Pamela; Rich, Mark S.; Richman, Susan; Risenhoover, C.C.; Roberts, Tim; Robertson, Robert L.; Rollo, Ned; Rosen, Dan; Rost, Stephen; Routt, Edd; Correspondence about book reviews, author requests, thank you letters, photograph
  - Rabe, Stephen [University of Texas at Dallas], 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Railey, Walter, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Rechy, John, 1983-1992 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Correspondence about books written (author), copies of newspaper articles
  - Redd, Louise, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Reynolds, Clay, 1986-1997 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Rigler, Judyth, 1984-1987 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Roach, Joyce, 1989-1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Roberts, Kent, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Rodriguez, Richard, 1982-2000 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Rossiter, Frank [University of Texas at Dallas], 1976-1980 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Rubin, Louis [Algonquin Books], 1986-1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Runnels, Steve, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Rushing, Jane, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - S, 1969-1998 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Salazar, Ramiros; Sall, Larry D.; Schaefer, Frank; Schirmer, Gregory A.; Seagraves, Eleanor R.; Seale, Jan Epton; Shaffer, Richard A.; Shant, Jane; Shapard, Robert; Shattuck, Robert D.; Shepard, Martin; Sherman, Laurel G.; Shuford, Gene; Sigwald, John; Simmons, Tom J.; Simpson, Henry; Slattery, Dennis; Sloan, Ledgerwood; Snodgrass, E.H.; Snyder, Bill; Snyder, Marion S.; St. John, Bob; Stacy, Dennis; Stapleton, Tom; Stevenson, Margaret; Stott, William M.; Stuckey, Bill; Swank, Patsy; Swindle, Howard; Correspondence about book reviews, author requests, thank you letters, photograph
  - Sallis, James, 1981-1994 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Sampson, Curt, 1991-1995 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Sanders, Bob Ray, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)